benchmarkemail.in 2014-06-26

# Privacy Policy - Benchmark Email

## Where we stand on gathering, sharing and protecting your info

#### Privacy Policy for Benchmark Email

Effective Date: 12/14/2012

Welcome to Benchmark Email, owned and operated by Benchmark Internet Group, LLC (herein after referred to as "Benchmark," "company," "us," "we," and/or "our").

This document/page lays out our privacy policy in regards to information that we may collect on our website www.benchmarkemail.com and through the associated Benchmark Email Service. This includes personally identifiable info (personal data). The use of information collected through our Service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which our customers have engaged us. Your data and privacy are of utmost importance to Benchmark, and this privacy policy was created to emphasize that. This policy will explain how we use and protect your personal data and any other information gathered with the service.

Benchmark Internet Group has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements and the TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [http://www.benchmarkemail.com](http://www.benchmarkemail.com/) and the associated Services.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe here, <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Benchmark Internet Group complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Benchmark has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Benchmark's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

If you are unsure about our privacy rules or this policy, please contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com).

#### Information We May Collect

When you sign up for a free account, we will ask you for information. This information may include:

  * Your name 
  * Your company name 
  * Your company or home address 
  * Your telephone number 
  * Your email address 
  * Your email list details 
  * How many emails you plan to send 
  * Whether you use good email marketing practices

Likewise, when you sign up for a paid plan, we will ask you for the same information as above, as well as:

  * The name on your credit card 
  * Your credit card number
  * Your credit card number expiration date 
  * The three or four-digit safety code on the back of your card 
  * Your billing address

In addition, if you contact us for more info on any of our partner programs, our non-profit discount program, our faith-based initiative discount program or other programs, we may also ask you:

  * Your non-profit's name 
  * Your non-profit's 501(c) number 
  * Your faith-based organization's name 
  * The size of your organization or congregation

Our website offers a publicly accessible blog and a member community forum. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Our community forum provides the ability to create a personal profile which gives you the option to submit additional personal and demographic information about yourself, such as age and personal interests. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Also available through our forum, you can choose to use our referral feature to tell a friend about our site. We will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email notifying him or her to the aspect of the site you wanted to share. Benchmark stores (or does not store) this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time. Your friend may contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

We also may display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us about using the information listed below.

#### Non-Personal, Non-Identifiable Data Collection

When you use or interact with our services, we may collect non-identifiable data, which may include but is not limited to type of Internet browser, Internet Protocol (IP addresses), geographic location (approximate), a record of how you use our services and sites, and other data that cannot be used to identify you. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

When you use our service or visit our site(s), we use something called a "cookie" that we place on your browser. This cookie can do anything from analyze how you use our service to automatically identifying you when you visit the site. This saves you time, because when a cookie is used, you may not need to enter in your password or login info over and over to use the service. Cookies are in no way linked to personally identifiable information.

In keeping with the EU Privacy and Electronic Communications Directive, here is a list of the cookies we use on Benchmark Email and a brief summary of what they do:

  * Benchmark Email session cookies: These cookies identify you as a logged-in user of the site and store preferences to enhance your user experience.
  * Cookies with prefix "_utm": Google Analytics cookies help us track visitors to our site, as well as their behavior during their visit.
  * Cookies with prefix "_km": KISSmetrics tracks user behavior across our site, including sales and free trial signups.
  * Adroll: AdRoll is a retargeting system that helps us identify prior users and show them ads on different websites, helping us to recapture previous visitors.
  * Sourcetracking: Helps us identify referring sites for our affiliate program.

These cookies may be used to tailor content to you when you visit our service or other sites in the future. Cookies may last for one browser session or many, and may even be used for months or even years until they expire. If you'd like to remove, disable or prevent cookies from being installed on your machine, use the help section of your Internet browser to find out how you can make adjustments to your cookie settings. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited. To save you time and to use our services to the fullest, we recommend that you keep your cookies turned on. Be advised, we may also be using HTML5 cookies in future updates to the service.

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other 3rd party assets (such as social media plug-ins) on the site is not covered by our privacy policy. These 3rd parties may use cookies, clear gifs, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our site. We do not have access or control over these technologies.

Additionally, we employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons) that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

#### What We Do with Your Information

We may use your personal information to:

  * Fulfill your registration/order/purchase
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Facilitate your communication with other users
  * List you in our member directory made available only to other members

In order to serve you better and deliver the features you like most, we may conduct research on customer interests, behavior and demographics, based on the personal data we have collected. This research will be studied and analyzed on an aggregate basis, which means it will not identify you personally. Hence, it is considered non-personal data under our privacy policy. 

#### Using Our Email Service

You can import contacts from various CRM systems and other email account address books to populate your email recipient lists. We collect the username and password for the account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose.

When sending emails via our service, we maintain strict privacy for all your data. Hence, if you upload or create an email list and store it online, and decide to purge or delete those email addresses, we do not keep them on our servers. They are gone forever, so please take note to export your data before you delete it if you may need to use it in the future.

While we may review your list when you upload it, just to make sure it's opt-in, we do not monitor or review the content beyond that first stage.

Also, when you create or upload an email list and store it with our service, **we do not sell, rent or give away the data on your list.** That data is yours and yours alone, we merely store it for you when you use our service.

#### Regarding 3rd Party Data Processes through Our Email Service

Benchmark collects information under the direction of our customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes as part of providing the Service. 

An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to the Benchmark customer they interact with directly (the data controller). If a Benchmark customer requests that we remove personally identifiable information on their behalf, we will respond to their request within 30 days. 

Benchmark will retain personal data we process on behalf of our customers for as long as needed to provide services and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### When and How We Share Your Information

Benchmark does not sell or market your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Benchmark will only disclose your data, the content of your private communications, or the contact information of your recipients if required to do so by law, or as otherwise stated in this Statement, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Benchmark; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Benchmark and others, including among other things to enforce our Terms of Service; (3) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of its members or the public; (4) to correct technical problems and malfunctions in how we provide our service to you and to technically process your information; (5) to take precautions against liability; (6) to respond to claims that information you have submitted to Benchmark has violated the rights or interests of a third party; or (7) as permitted by law or to provide information to law enforcement agencies. 

Also, certain technical processing of email messages and their content that are required for: (1) sending and receiving messages; (2) conforming to connecting networks' technical requirements; (3) conforming to the limitations of the Service; or (4) other similar technical connecting requirements.

It is possible that as we continue to develop our business, Benchmark may be acquired. In such a transaction, your information may be transferred to the acquiring entity. Should this happen, you will be notified via email and a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of your personal information. If as a result of the business transition your personally identifiable information will be used in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, you will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

Using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect, Twitter, Google and others, you may leave comments on our blog, reviews in our Marketplace, and Benchmark customers can integrate social media features into email campaigns. These services will authenticate your identity and may give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your social network.

#### User Access and Preferences

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend or delete/remove certain information by making the change in your user account settings portal, by emailing our Customer Support at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. We may also send our customers promotional emails occasionally. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com).

#### Security

The security of personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our site, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Our Service platform is also encrypted to protect the integrity of our customers' information.

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@benchmarkemail.com](mailto:support@benchmarkemail.com).

#### Links to Other Websites

Benchmark Email's web site, or messages created with Benchmark, may contain links to other Websites. Benchmark is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Websites. Third parties may independently collect information about you when you view ads or other communications from third parties through Benchmark products or services. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. If you do not want those companies to collect information about you, please contact them directly. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

Additionally, our web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, Tweet button, "Share This" and other interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

#### Benchmark Policy Changes

As with any business, we reserve the right to make changes to our privacy statement, polices and practices. Should this happen, we will notify you at least 30 days before those changes take place by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change. If these new policies and practices reflect something different than what we're already doing, we'll give you the choice, at least 30 days in advance of those changes, to either continue with us or cancel your service and go elsewhere. 

#### Contact Us 

Benchmark Email   
10621 Calle Lee, Building 141  
Los Alamitos, CA 90720, USA   
Phone: 800.430.4095
